Guide to the Yale College Records Concerning Student Discipline
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Yale College records concerning student discipline
1755-1865
RU 811
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
0.75
(2 boxes)
The materials consist of judgements, petitions, dismissals, correspondence, and confessions documenting student discipline at Yale.
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 41 (YRG 41), Material documenting Yale student life.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Arrangement
Arranged chronologically.
Scope and Contents
The materials consist of judgements, petitions, dismissals, correspondence, and confessions documenting student discipline at Yale.
College discipline; College students; Yale College (1718-1887) -- Students
- Student discipline records, Accession 1979-A-038
  - Testimony of John Lothrop (Class of 1762), circa 1760 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Confession of Joseph Marsh (Class of 1763), circa 1761 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Confession of James Nichols, circa1771 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Confession of John Brown, 1771 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Judgement Against [?] Balding, 1771 March 1 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Petition of the Class of 1787, circa 1787 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Verdict of Six Members of the Class of 1787: Clark, McCurdy, Griswold, Lathrop, Goodrich, Butler, 1786 June 21 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Confession of Asahel Morris, Elijah, Paine, William Reynolds, John Stearnes (Class of 1789), 1787 July 6 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Confession of Silas Merriman (Class of 1789), 1788 October 30 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Expulsion of James H. Fitch, 1788 October 30 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Class of 1791, 1791 January 10 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Case of Elijah Waterman, 1791 February 9 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Rustification of Bates and Fitch, 1792 March 27 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Rustification of Nathan Sanford, 1794 July 12 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Rustification of Seth Lewis Hunt, 1794 July 16 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Confession of Caleb Woodhull (Class of 1812), 1810 May 8 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Confession of Isaac Preston (Class of 1812), 1810 October 28 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Remarks by James Ellsworth Dekay, 1812 February 19 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Expulsion of James Ellsworth Dekay, 1812 February 20 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Apology of P. Pomeroy, 1816 February 19 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Petition for P. Pomeroy, 1816 Feb? (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Dismissal of William Molinaur, 1816 April 22 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Confession of William T. Gould, circa 1816 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Confession of Edward P. Terry, 1817 May 5 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Confession of A. Maryck, 1817 May (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Dismissal of Norris M. Jones, 1817 December 3 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Petition of Norris M. Jones, 1817 December 4 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Petition for Norris M. Jones, 1817 December (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Confession of Robert Kortright, 1817 May 2 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Confession of William Hume, 1817 May 5 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Confession of John Sanford, 1817 May 5 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Confession of P. Phelps Sanford, 1817 May 5 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Class of 1820 Petition for James, 1818 March (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Confessions of John P. Williston, 1818 June 3, 1818 June 22 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Expulsion of Bedford, William J. B., 1818 August 26 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Confessions of Walter Livingston and Maltby Strong (Class of 1819), 1818 November 23 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Confession of William Avery, 1819 December 1 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Confession of Joseph A. Hill (Class of 1819), circa 1819 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - John T. Kirkland, President of Harvard University Re Case of Norris M. Jones, 1819 December 9, 1820 January 19 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Confession of Mason Brown, 1820 March 4 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Confession of Theodore C. Cone, 1820 April 12 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Confession of Thomas P. Little, 1820 June (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Confession of George W. Peter, 1820 September 11 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Confession of Edward Rockwell, 1820 September (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Confession of William Wright, 1821 March 20 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Expulsion of Alfred N. Bullitt, 1821 June 29 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Expulsion of Isaac A. Mills, 1821 June 29 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Confession of [W. F. Harding?], 1821 June 25 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Confession of [Otho?] Eichelberger, circa 1820's (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Confession of William E. Laight, circa 1820's (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Confession of Alfred Terry, circa 1821 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Petition, circa 1821 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Confession of Joseph H. [Spayd?], 1823 January 26 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Acknowledgement of Lewis C. [Troservant?], 1823 February 15 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Confession of Edward Laurens, 1823 July 22 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Acknowledgement by C. C. Livingston, 1823 July 25 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Confession of Edward Kneeland, 1823 July (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Confession of Moses Atwater, 1823 July (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Confession of LeRoy Pope, 1823 August 29 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Expulsion of [?] Kneeland, 1823 October 28 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Expulsion of [?] Boardman, 1823 November 17 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - From Freshman Class Re Boardman, 1823 November 20 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Confession of [D.?] H. Proper, 1823 December (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Confession of Eliezer Crane, 1823 December (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Confession of William W. Dwight, 1823 December (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Confession of Elizur Wright, 1823 December (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Petition of the Class of 1823 for Whitmill J. Hill, undated (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Two Petitions of Sophomore Class (1826) for Josiah Collins, 1824 January 3, 1824 January (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Petition of the Class of 1824, 1824 January (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Confession of William M. Lathrop, 1824 February 16 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Confession of Ebeneezer Parker, circa 1825 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Confession of Thomas O. Lincoln, 1826 March (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Petition for Thomas O. Lincoln, by Class of 1828, circa 1826 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Confession of Joel T. Case, 1826 November 2 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Apology of John F. Boardman, 1826 December 30 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Dismissal of N. Willard Bishop, 1827 July 21 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Confession of [?] Trumbull, 1827 August 23 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Expulsion of Paul Simpson, 1828 August 5 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Expulsion of John Henry and D. Nicholson Hennen, 1828 January 24 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Confession of Thomas A. Spence, 1828 October 24 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Confession of Samuel Gile, Jr., circa 1828 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Expulsion of A. Drisdale and James W. Wallace, 1829 March 23 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Dismissal of A. M. Pena, 1829 July 29 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Confession of R. O. Colt and J. O. Colt, 1829 December 2 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Confession of George G. Barclay, 1829 December 4 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Confession of A. E. Forstall, 1829 December 4 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Minutes of Inquiries, Evidence, Note Regarding the Breaking of Windows, 1830 March (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Expulsion of William F. Barnard Regarding Broken Windows, 1830 March 14 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Affidavits Regarding Broken Windows: (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Edward S. Mosely and John R. Crane, 1830 March 20 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - William F. Barnard, 1830 March 22 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Petitions of the Freshman Class, Edward S. Mosely, John R. Crane, Samuel Henshaw Bates, George B. Hawley (2 items) Regarding the Breaking of Windows, 1830 March (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Petition of the Senior Class on behalf of Oliver Ellsworth, 1830 July (Box 2, Folder 37a)
  - Freshman Petition for William E. Hancock, 1831 February (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Sophomore Petition for [?] A. Smith, 1831 February (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Senior Petition for [?] A. Smith, 1831 February (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Petition of the Class of 1833 for Robert Robertson, circa 1831 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Confession of [?] Wilkinson, 1832 October (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Acknowledgement of Alexander Van Rensselaer and Edward H. Van Wyck, 1832 December 25 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Petition of the Sophomore Class of 1832 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Petition of Senior Class for John C. Raffety, 1835 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Confession of Amos [?], 1835 November 11 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Expulsion of William A. Hauser, 1837 February 17 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Dismission of Samual Polk, 1838 January 1 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Petition of the Senior Class for Samual Polk, 1838 January (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Petition of the Sophomore Class for Julius H. Pratt, 1839 November (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Expulsion of Thomas L. Leeds, 1840 December 2 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Petition of the Class of 1840 for Giles Deshon and Oscar Noyes, circa 1840 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Expulsion of Robert R. Howard, 1842 February 4 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Petition of the Senior Class for John A. Lent, 1842 September (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Report on Russell Smith and Rufus Smith, 1843 March 23 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Expulsion of Louis Fassitt, 1843 October 5 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Petition of the Class of 1847 for [?] White, 1844 November 13 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - To Henry Blodget from James A. Smith, 1852 April 13 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - To Henry Blodget from L. Baldwin, 1852 April 14 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - To Henry Blodget from O. Gibson, 1852 April 16 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - To Henry Blodget from [?] Gibson, 1852 April 16 (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - To Henry Blodget from R. M. McClellan, 1852 April 28 (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - To Henry Blodget for Beda Dorman, 1852 May 5 (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - To the Faculty of Yale College from Lester M. Dorman, 1852 May 6 (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - To Henry Blodget from R. Miller McClellan, 1852 May 8 (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - To the Faculty of Yale College from H. Baldwin, 1852? (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Petition of D. J. Holms, circa 1853 (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Petition of William H. L. Barnes, 1854 December 13 (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Acknowledgement from Henry Gorton and William D. Anderson, 1853 October 28? (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Petition of the Class of 1866 Re Hazing, 1863 June 10 (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - Petition of the Class of 1867 Re Hazing, circa 1865 (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - Acknowledgement, Not Signed, undated (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - Acknowledgement, [Gibson?], May 7 (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - Confession of [Albert Russel?], undated (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - Professor Kingsley's Bully Law, undated (Box 2, Folder 52)
- Student excuses, Accession 19ND-A-433; 0.25; (1 box) (Box 1)